Delivery plans change. Driver authority should not.
PITT keeps the route visible while traffic, weather, work zones, and fuel conditions move.
Navigation finds a route. PITT adds the decision layer: time windows, reserve, detours, and a reviewable record.
At each predicted arrival, PITT checks moving traffic, weather, and road-work patterns. Fuel decisions compare pump price against detour cost. Every signal in this prototype is seeded, not live.
Outcome one. The price rises. PITT recalculates and waits. The driver chooses refuel. The reserve recovers.
Outcome two. At the price hike, the driver passes. The route advances. Later, the price drops. Now the stop is worthwhile, so the driver selects the refuel stop.
Outcome three. The tank was already filled that morning. At the first fuel offer, PITT checks again, but another stop is not worth the detour. The driver passes. Later, a lower pump price appears. The saving is only $2.73, against $16.80 of detour cost. PITT marks the second stop not cost-worthy, and the driver passes again.
Outcome four. The driver passes the first offer, then passes the second. After the next leg, fuel reaches zero. PITT blocks progress. The driver closes the route early, and the remaining stops stay undelivered.
Behind the scenes, Codex and GPT-5.6 helped shape the rules, add the missing economic branch, and test all four outcomes in the browser. It also provided encouragement and moral support when the demo fought back. Every consequential action remains behind driver review.
PITT produces a reviewable report and local machine handoff. It contacts no carrier and controls no vehicle without an approved next step.
And yes. PITT is aware of magic roundabouts. Swindon still gets human review... and possibly a wizard.